RUTH LUNA CARVAJAL



- 23 Hillview Drive, R93PX05, Carlow
- +353834297625
- ruth.luna@outlook.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Bachelor of Business Administration with more than 12 years experience on different roles on the accounting and management area.

Quick-learning worker committed to accuracy, efficiency and continual improvement.

Expertise in the full accounting process from identify and record transactions to closing the books.

Comprehensive knowledge of invoicing, accounts payable and receivable, reconciliation, cash-flow, VAT, and VIES.

Advanced technology skills on Microsoft 365 focus on productivity, collaboration and analytics tools, and ERP SAGE 50 & SAGE Payroll for accounting, invoicing and payroll among others finances software.

WORK HISTORY

Business owner, 10/2020 - 12/2021

Self-employed, Carlow

- Managed legal and financial documentation (Sole trader and VAT registration, business name registration, ROS registration, open business bank account, and contract payment gateway), invoicing as well as managed vCards project with a team of four people using Microsoft Teams.
 - vCards was a membership software based in a subscription payment model which provided associations, clubs and other membership organizations with tools and automated processes to manage and engage their members. They could manage member data in a database, create, renew, upgrade and downgrade memberships, communicate with their members by customized emails and each member had a virtual card (ID) with a QR code to validate that the person belongs to the organization.
- Elaborated Business Plan: business description, market analysis, marketing and sales strategy, and financial projection.
- Prepared and file taxes on Revenue Online Services (VAT, VIES and FORM 11).

Accounting Technician, 10/2015 - 05/2019

Pato Piscinas LTD, Huelva (Spain)

Activity: Swimming pools constructions and maintenance.

Nº employees: 15-20

 When I started to work in the company an agency was in charge of accounting, there were a lot of documents in the office mixed and unfiled some of them invoices and transactions not delivered to the agency therefore no recorded, and there was not control over the works costs.

In 1 and half month, I searched and implemented two software, one to control inventory and works costs and another for the accounting and financial area, talked to the construction workers so they understood the importance of fill the labor and materials form every day and how do it, reconciliated all accounts for the last 4 years and updated the accounting.

Construction cost reports helped the owner make more accurate budgets for customers, that together with my management on accounts receivable and payable increased profit. In 2015 the profit was around 11,000€ in 2016 14,000€

- Managed record transactions, maintained fixed asset register, capital
 expenditure records and depreciation journals, invoicing, accounts payable and
 receivable, cash flow forecasting and accounts reconciliation (including banks).
- Prepared and filed taxes, prepared financial reports, and year-end closing.

Accounting Technician, 11/2012 - 03/2015

SUMO, Huelva (Spain)

Activity: Supply of industrial products, industrial maintenance works, and auxiliary works for neighborhood communities.

Nº employees: 30-35

- Managed record transactions, maintained fixed asset register, capital
 expenditure records and depreciation journals, invoicing, accounts payable and
 receivable, cash flow forecasting and accounts reconciliation (including banks).
- Prepared and filed taxes, prepared financial reports, and year-end closing.
- Grant management.

Management and Common Services Technician, 11/2011 - 03/2012

Statistics National Institute, Huelva (Spain)

Activity: Statistics (Public Sector)

Collected and recorded data for population and housing census.

Administrative Assistant, 10/2008 - 01/2009 Statistics National Institute, Huelva (Spain)

Activity: Statistics (Public Sector)

• Recorded statistic data.

Technical office assistant, 12/2007 - 07/2008 Huelva County Council, Huelva (Spain) Activity: Architecture (Public Sector)

 Document management for an architect, a quantity surveyor and two draftsmen.

Accounting Bookkeeper, 06/2002 - 08/2006 ENSA Group (6 companies), Huelva (Spain)

Activity: Industrial electrical projects, renewable energy an integral water cycle, industrial automation, special electrical panels, repair of large high-power and voltage electrical engines and generators, as well as industrial supplies.

N° employees: 110-120

- Managed record transactions, maintained fixed asset register, capital
 expenditure records and depreciation journals, invoicing, accounts payable and
 receivable, cash flow forecasting and accounts reconciliation (including banks).
- Prepared taxes, prepared financial reports, and year-end closing.
- Collaborated in the development of work procedures and internal audits.

Administrative Assistant, 06/2001 - 12/2001 ENSA Group (6 companies), Huelva (Spain)

- Charge costs to work orders.
- Work orders cost control.
- · Invoicing.

SKILLS

- Accounting skills
- Problem-solving skills.
- Attention to detail.
- Adaptability.

- Commitment.
- Microsoft 365.
- Accounting software: SAGE Contaplus, SAGE Facturaplus, SAGE 50, SAGE Payroll, Contasol and Factusol.

EDUCATION

IBAT College Dublin, Dublin, 04/2022 Diploma in Bookkeeping and Payroll

Score of 100% in both exams. Skills in SAGE 50 and SAGE Payroll.

Further Education and Training Award, Carlow, 06/2021

Communication Level 3: English language

Carlow Kilkenny Skillnet, Carlow, 02/2021 Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Further Education and Training Award, Carlow, 12/2019

Communications Level 2: English language

Educanet, Huelva (Spain), 04/2018

GDPR: Data Protection

Educanet, Huelva (Spain), 12/2016

Accounting Analytics

Santa Maria La Real Fundation, Huelva, 06/2015 Personal Productivity

Soportecc, Huelva (Spain), 06/2011

Payroll

University of Huelva, Huelva (Spain), 12/2001

Bachelor of Business Administration